Sync by
jin5a@naver.com
l can't let you out, Hedwig.
,
I'm not allowed to use magic
outside of school.
- Besides, if Uncle Vernon--
- Harry Potter!
..
/ !
Now you've done it.
He's in there. Vernon?
,
/
I'm warning you, if you can't control
that bloody bird, it'll have to go.
But she's bored.
lf l could only let her out
for an hour or two.
..
?
So you can send secret messages
to your freaky little friends? No, sir.
But l haven't had any messages
from any of my friends.
Not one...
...all summer.
Who would want to be
friends with you?
?
l should think you'd be
a little more grateful.
We've raised you since you were a baby,
given you the food off our table...
...even let you have
Dudley's second bedroom...
...purely out of the goodness
of our hearts.
- Not now. It's for when the Masons arrive.
- Which should be any minute.
Now, let's go over our schedule
once again, shall we?
,
?
Petunia, when the Masons arrive,
you will be...?
,
?
In the lounge, waiting to welcome
them graciously to our home.
,
- Good. And, Dudley, you will be...?
- I'll be waiting to open the door.
,
?
Excellent.
And you?
?
I'll be in my bedroom, making no noise
and pretending that l don't exist.
Too right, you will.
With any luck, this could be the day
l make the biggest deal of my career...
...and you will not mess it up.
Harry Potter, such an honor it is.
,
- Who are you?
- Dobby, sir. Dobby the house-elf.
?
Not to be rude or anything...
...but this isn't a great time for me
to have a house-elf in my bedroom.
,
Yes, sir. Dobby understands.
It's just that Dobby
has come to tell you...
It is difficult, sir.
Dobby wonders where to begin.
..
- Why don't you sit down?
- Sit down? Sit down?
?
, ?
Dobby, I'm sorry. l didn't mean
to offend you or anything.
, ,
Offend Dobby?
..
?
Dobby has heard
of your greatness, sir...
...but never has he been asked
to sit down by a wizard, like an equal.
You can't have met
many decent wizards then.
No, l haven't.
,
That was an awful thing to say.
..
, ..
- Bad Dobby! Bad Dobby!
- Stop, Dobby. Dobby, shush.
,
Dobby, please, stop.
Don't mind that. It's just the cat.
- Bad Dobby.
- Stop! Stop, Dobby. Please, be quiet.
..
/ ,
Are you all right?
?
Dobby had to punish himself, sir.
Dobby almost spoke ill
of his family, sir.
?
- Your family?
- The wizard family Dobby serves, sir.
Dobby is bound to serve
one family forever.
?
lf they ever knew Dobby was here...
But Dobby had to come. Dobby has
to protect Harry Potter. To warn him.
Harry Potter must not go back...
,
...to Hogwarts School
of Witchcraft and Wizardry this year.
There is a plot, a plot to make
most terrible things happen.
What terrible things?
Who's plotting them?
?
. .
Can't say.
- Okay, l understand. You can't say.
- Don't make me talk. l--
,
- Dobby. Dobby, put the lamp down.
- Bad Dobby.
So when they arrive
at the ninth hole...
..
Give me the lamp.
Dobby, stop!
,
- Let me go.
- Get in there and keep quiet.
- What the devil are you doing up here?
- l was just--
?
..
You just ruined the punch line
of my Japanese golfer joke.
Sorry.
One more sound and you'll wish
you'd never been born, boy.
- And fix that door.
- Yes, sir.
See why I've got to go back?
?
l don't belong here.
l belong in your world, at Hogwarts.
- It's the only place I've got friends.
- Friends who don't write to Harry Potter?
?
Well, l expect they've been...
..
Hang on. How do you know
my friends haven't been writing to me?
,
?
Harry Potter mustn't
be angry with Dobby.
,
Dobby hoped if Harry Potter
thought his friends had forgotten him...
...Harry Potter might not want
to go back to school, sir.
- Give me those. Now.
- No!
Dobby, get back here.
,
Dobby, please, no.
Harry Potter must say
he's not going back to school.
,
l can't. Hogwarts is my home.
Then Dobby must do it, sir,
for Harry Potter's own good.
It spread as far as the eye could see,
all over the floor of this building.
One plumber said,
"Look at all that water."
The second plumber said,
"Yes, and that's just the top of it."
I'm so sorry. It's my nephew.
He's very disturbed.
,
..
Meeting strangers upsets him.
That's why l kept him upstairs.
You're never going back to that school.
You're never going to see those
freaky friends of yours again. Never!
!
Hiya, Harry.
, ?
Ron. Fred. George.
What are you all doing here?
,
?
Rescuing you, of course.
Now, come on, get your trunk.
You better stand back.
Let's go.
- What was that?
- What was it?
Potter!
!
Dad, what's going on?
Go. Go. Go.
Dad, hurry up.
- Come on.
- Come on, Harry, hurry up.
,
Petunia, he's escaping!
!
- I've got you, Harry.
- Come here!
- Let go of me!
- No, boy!
/
You and that bloody pigeon
aren't going anywhere.
!
- Get off!
- Drive!
- Right.
- Right!
No! No! No! No!
Dad!
Damn.
By the way, Harry, happy birthday.
,
Come on.
Okay, come on.
,
- Think it'd be all right if we had some?
- Yeah, Mum will never know.
It's not much, but it's home.
l think it's brilliant.
Where have you been?
?
Harry, how wonderful
to see you, dear.
,
Beds empty. No note. Car gone.
You could have died.
You could have been seen.
Of course, l don't
blame you, Harry, dear.
,
They were starving him, Mum.
There were bars on his window.
,
Well, you best hope l don't put bars
on your window, Ronald Weasley.
,
Come on, Harry,
time for a spot of breakfast.
,
Here we are, Harry. Now, tuck in.
That's it. There we go.
- Mummy, have you seen my jumper?
- Yes, dear, it was on the cat.
, ?
,
Hello.
?
What did l do?
Ginny. She's been talking about you
all summer. A bit annoying, really.
,
, !
- Morning, Weasleys.
- Morning, Dad.
, !
,
- What a night. Nine raids. Nine!
- Raids?
?
Dad works in the Ministry of Magic,
in the Misuse of Muggle Artifacts Office.
Dad loves Muggles,
thinks they're fascinating.
Well, now.
And who are you?
?
Sorry, sir. I'm Harry, sir.
Harry Potter.
,
Good Lord. Are you really?
?
Well, Ron has told us all about you,
of course. When did he get here?
?
This morning.
Your sons flew that enchanted car
of yours to Surrey and back last night.
?
Did you really? How did it go?
l mean-- That was very wrong
indeed, boys. Very wrong of you.
,
Now, Harry, you must know
all about Muggles.
,
?
Tell me, what exactly
is the function of a rubber duck?
Well, that'll be Errol with the post.
Fetch it, will you, Percy, please?
,
- Errol.
- He's always doing that.
,
?
Look, it's our Hogwarts letters.
They've sent us Harry's as well.
,
Dumbledore must know you're here.
Doesn't miss a trick, that man.
,
?
- No.
- This lot won't come cheap.
,
- The spell books alone are very expensive.
- We'll manage.
There's only one place we're going to
get all of this. Diagon Alley.
Right.
Here we are, Harry.
You go first, dear.
,
But Harry's never traveled
by Floo powder before, Mum.
,
Floo powder?
?
,
You go first, Ron, so that Harry
can see how it's done. Yes.
In you go.
That's it.
" "
Diagon Alley.
You see? It's quite easy, dear.
Don't be afraid. Come on.
, ?
,
Come on.
In you go. That's it. Mind your head.
That's right.
Now, take your Floo powder.
,
That's it, very good.
Now, don't forget to speak
very, very clearly.
" "
Diagonally.
- What did he say, dear?
- Diagonally.
, ?
l thought he did.
- Not lost, are you, my dear?
- I'm fine, thank you. l was just going...
, ?
..
Come with us. We'll help you
find your way back.
- No. Please--
- Harry?
,
?
Hagrid!
!
What do you think
you're doing down here? Come on.
?
You're a mess, Harry. Skulking around
Knockturn Alley? Dodgy place.
Don't want no one to see you there.
People will think you're up to no good.
l was lost, l--
Hang on. What were you
doing down there then?
?
Me? l was... l was looking
for Flesh-Eating Slug Repellent.
?
They're ruining all the school cabbages.
Harry. Hagrid.
!
, ?
Hello, Hermione.
- It's so good to see you.
- It's great to see you too.
What did you do to your glasses?
?
Oculus Reparo,
" "
l definitely need to remember that one.
You'll be all right now then, Harry?
Right. I'll leave you to it.
, ?
- Okay, bye.
- Thank you. Bye.
Come on, everyone's been so worried.
,
Harry.
Thank goodness. We'd hoped
you'd only gone one grate too far.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. Gilderoy Lockhart.
,
Here he is.
Mum fancies him.
,
Make way there, please.
Let me by, madam. Thank you.
,
Excuse me, little girl.
This is for the Daily Prophet.
,
It can't be. Harry Potter?
Harry Potter!
!
Excuse me, madam.
Nice big smile, Harry.
Together, you and l rate the front page.
Ladies and gentlemen,
what an extraordinary moment this is.
,
?
When young Harry stepped
into Flourish and Blotts this morning...
...to purchase my autobiography,
Magical Me...
' '
...which, incidentally,
is currently celebrating...
...its 27th week atop
the Daily Prophet bestseller list...
...he had no idea that he would,
in fact, be leaving...
...with my entire collected works...
...free of charge.
Now, ladies?
Harry, now you give me those,
and I'll get them signed.
,
All of you wait outside.
That's it.
,
I'll bet you loved that,
didn't you, Potter?
,
Famous Harry Potter. Can't even go into
a bookshop without making the front page.
Leave him alone.
Look, Potter.
You've got yourself a girlfriend.
,
Now, now, Draco, play nicely.
Mr. Potter.
Lucius Malfoy. We meet at last.
Forgive me.
Your scar is legend.
As, of course, is the wizard
who gave it to you.
Voldemort killed my parents.
He was nothing more than a murderer.
You must be very brave
to mention his name.
Or very foolish.
Fear of a name only increases
fear of the thing itself.
And you must be Miss Granger.
Yes, Draco has told me
all about you. And your parents.
Muggles, aren't they?
?
Let me see.
Red hair, vacant expressions...
,
...tatty, secondhand book.
You must be the Weasleys.
It's mad in here.
Let's go outside.
,
- Well, well, well. Weasley senior.
- Lucius.
, ?
Busy time at the Ministry, Arthur,
all those extra raids?
?
l do hope they're paying you overtime...
...but judging by the state of this,
l'd say not.
What's the use in being a disgrace
to the name of wizard...
...if they don't even pay you well for it?
We have a very different idea about what
disgraces the name of wizard, Malfoy.
,
Clearly.
Associating with Muggles.
And l thought your family
could sink no lower.
I'll see you at work.
See you at school.
- 10:58. Come on.
- The train will be leaving any moment.
10 50
Fred, George, Percy, you first.
, ,
Okay.
After you, dear.
Come on, Ginny,
we'll get you a seat. Hurry.
,
Let's go.
?
- What do you two think you're doing?
- Sorry.
Lost control of the trolley.
- Why can't we get through?
- l don't know.
?
,
The gateway has sealed
itself for some reason.
The train leaves at exactly 11:00.
We've missed it.
,
Harry, if we can't get through...
...maybe Mum and Dad can't get back.
Maybe we should just go
and wait by the car.
The car.
?
Ron, l should tell you...
,
...most Muggles aren't accustomed
to seeing a flying car.
,
Right.
Okay.
,
Oh, no! The Invisibility Booster
must be faulty.
Come on, then. Let's go lower.
We need to find the train.
,
Okay.
All we need to do is catch up
with the train.
We can't be far behind.
?
- Do you hear that?
- We must be getting close.
Hold on.
Harry!
!
Hold on!
Take my hand!
!
Hold on!
I'm trying. Your hand's all sweaty.
- l think we found the train.
- Yeah.
Welcome home.
Up! Up!
!
It's not working!
Up! Ron, mind that tree!
!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
, !
- My wand. Look at my wand.
- Be thankful it's not your neck.
- What's happening?
- l don't know.
?
Come on, go! Fast!
Scabbers, you're okay.
, ?
!
The car!
Dad's gonna kill me.
See you, Hedwig.
,
So a house-elf shows up
in my bedroom...
...we can't get through the barrier
to platform 9 3/4...
9 3/4
...we almost get killed by a tree...
Clearly someone doesn't want me
here this year.
Well, take a good look, lads.
This night might well be
the last you spend in this castle.
Oh, dear, we are in trouble.
You were seen by no less
than seven Muggles.
Do you have any idea
how serious this is?
?
You have risked
the exposure of our world.
Not to mention the damage you
inflicted on a Whomping Willow...
...that's been on these grounds
since before you were born.
Honestly, Professor Snape,
l think it did more damage to us.
Silence.
!
l assure you that were you in Slytherin,
and your fate rested with me...
...the both of you would be
on the train home tonight.
- As it is--
- They are not.
?
Professor Dumbledore.
Professor McGonagall.
Headmaster...
...these boys have flouted the Decree
for the Restriction of Underage Wizardry.
- As such--
- l am well aware of our bylaws, Severus...
...having written
quite a few of them myself.
However, as head of Gryffindor house...
...it is for Professor McGonagall
to determine the appropriate action.
We'll go and get our stuff, then.
?
What are you
talking about, Mr. Weasley?
You're going to expel us, aren't you?
?
Not today, Mr. Weasley...
,
...but l must impress on both of you
the seriousness of what you have done.
l will be writing to your families tonight,
and you will both receive detention.
Morning, everyone.
, ?
- Good morning, everyone.
- Good morning, Professor Sprout.
!
Welcome to Greenhouse Three,
second years. Gather around, everyone.
,
Today we're going to re-pot Mandrakes.
Who here can tell me
the properties of the Mandrake root?
?
Yes, Miss Granger?
,
Mandrake, or Mandragora...
...is used to return those who have been
Petrified to their original state.
It's also quite dangerous. The Mandrake's
cry is fatal to anyone who hears it.
Excellent. Ten points to Gryffindor.
,
As our Mandrakes
are still only seedlings...
...their cries won't kill you yet.
But they could knock you out for several hours,
which is why l have given you earmuffs...
...for auditory protection.
So could you please put them on,
right away? Quickly.
Flaps tight down,
and watch me closely.
You grasp your Mandrake firmly.
You pull it sharply up out of the pot.
Got it? And...
...now you dunk it down
into the other pot...
...and pour a little sprinkling of soil
to keep him warm.
Longbottom's been neglecting
his earmuffs.
- No, ma'am, he's just fainted.
- Yes, well, just leave him there.
,
Right, on we go.
Plenty of pots to go around.
Grasp your Mandrake and pull it up.
- There's Nearly Headless Nick.
- Hello, Percy, Miss Clearwater.
, ?
Hello, Sir Nicholas.
Say it. I'm doomed.
- You're doomed.
- Hi, Harry.
, ?
,
I'm Colin Creevey. I'm in Gryffindor too.
Hi, Colin. Nice to meet you.
,
?
Ron, is that your owl?
Bloody bird's a menace.
?
Oh, no.
,
Look, everyone.
Weasley's got himself a Howler.
Go on, Ron. l ignored one
from my gran once. It was horrible.
,
Ronald Weasley!
!
How dare you steal that car!
l am absolutely disgusted!
?
!
Your father's now facing
an inquiry at work...
!
...and it's entirely your fault!
lf you put another toe out of line...
!
...we'll bring you straight home!
And, Ginny, dear, congratulations
on making Gryffindor,
,
Your father and l are so proud,
Let me introduce you to your new
Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.
Me.
Gilderoy Lockhart...
...Order of Merlin, Third Class...
, 3
...honorary member
of the Dark Force Defense League...
...and five times winner...
...of Witch Weekly's
Most-Charming-Smile Award.
But l don't talk about that.
l didn't get rid of the Bandon Banshee
by smiling at him.
Now, be warned.
,
It is my job to arm you...
...against the foulest creatures
known to wizardkind.
You may find yourselves facing
your worst fears in this room.
Know only that no harm
can befall you whilst l am here.
,
l must ask you not to scream.
It might provoke them.
!
Cornish pixies?
?
Freshly caught Cornish pixies.
Laugh if you will, Mr. Finnegan...
...but pixies can be
devilishly tricky little blighters.
Let's see what you make of them.
Come on now, round them up.
They're only pixies.
- You just stay there!
- Please, get me down!
- Get off me!
- Stop. Hold still!
Peskipiksi Pesternomi!
I'll ask you three to just nip
the rest of them back into their cage.
What do we do now?
?
" "!
lmmobulus!
?
Why is it always me?
l spent the summer devising
a whole new Quidditch program.
,
We're gonna train earlier,
harder and longer.
What--? l don't believe it.
?
/
- Where you think you're going, Flint?
- Quidditch practice.
, ?
- l booked the pitch for Gryffindor today.
- Easy, Wood. I've got a note.
,
l smell trouble.
?
"l, Professor Severus Snape,
do hereby give the Slytherin team...
' '
'
...permission to practice today, owing
to the need to train their new Seeker."
'
You've got a new Seeker. Who?
?
- Malfoy?
- That's right.
?
,
And that's not all
that's new this year.
Those are Nimbus 2001s.
How did you get those?
?
A gift from Draco's father.
, ?
You see, Weasley, unlike some,
my father can afford the best.
At least no one on the Gryffindor team
had to buy their way in.
They got in on pure talent.
No one asked your opinion,
you filthy little Mudblood.
You'll pay for that one, Malfoy.
Eat slugs!
" "
You okay, Ron?
, ?
Say something.
,
- Wow! Can you turn him around, Harry?
- No, Colin, get out of the way.
,
Let's take him to Hagrid's.
He'll know what to do.
This calls for
a specialist's equipment.
Nothing to do but wait till it stops,
I'm afraid.
- Okay.
- Better out than in.
?
- Who was Ron trying to curse, anyway?
- Malfoy. He called Hermione...
?
Well, l don't know
exactly what it means.
He called me a Mudblood.
?
- He did not.
- What's a Mudblood?
?
It means "dirty blood." Mudblood's a really
foul name for someone who's Muggle-born.
Someone with non-magic parents.
Someone like me.
It's not a term one usually hears
in civilized conversation.
See, the thing is, Harry, there are
some wizards, like the Malfoy family...
,
...who think they're better than everyone
else because they're pure-blood.
That's horrible.
It's disgusting.
And it's codswallop to boot.
Dirty blood.
Why, there isn't a wizard alive today
that's not half-blood or less.
More to the point, they've yet to think
of a spell that our Hermione can't do.
Come here.
Don't you think on it, Hermione.
Don't you think on it for one minute.
,
?
Harry, Harry, Harry.
, ,
Can you possibly imagine...
...a better way to serve detention...
?
...than by helping me
to answer my fan mail?
Not really.
Fame is a fickle friend, Harry.
Celebrity is as celebrity does.
Remember that.
Come.
".."
Come...
...to me.
".."
" "
?
- What?
- Sorry?
?
That voice.
Voice?
?
- Didn't you hear it?
- What are you talking about, Harry?
?
l think you're getting
a bit drowsy.
And great Scott, no wonder. Look at the
time. We've been here nearly four hours.
Spooky how the time flies
when one is having fun.
?
Spooky.
Blood.
l smell blood.
Let me rip you.
Let me kill you.
" .."
Kill!
- Kill!
- Harry!
- Did you hear it?
- Hear what?
?
- That voice.
- Voice? What voice?
?
l heard it first in Lockhart's office.
And then again just--
..
It's time.
It's moving.
l think it's going to kill.
- Kill?
- Harry, wait! Not so fast!
?
, !
Strange.
- I've never seen spiders act like that.
- l don't like spiders.
?
What's that?
"The Chamber of Secrets has been
opened. Enemies of the Heir, beware."
'
, '
It's written in blood.
Oh, no.
It's Filch's cat.
It's Mrs. Norris.
"Enemies of the Heir, beware."
?
,
You'll be next, Mudbloods.
What's going on here?
Go on. Make way, make way.
?
,
Potter?
What are you...?
..
Mrs. Norris?
?
- You've murdered my cat.
- No. No.
I'll kill you.
- I'll kill you!
- Argus!
!
, ..
Argus, l...
Everyone will proceed
to their dormitories immediately.
,
Everyone except...
...you three.
,
Ravenclaws, follow me.
She's not dead, Argus.
She has been Petrified.
Thought so.
So unlucky l wasn't there.
l know exactly the countercurse
that could've spared her.
But how she has been Petrified,
l cannot say.
?
Ask him.
It's him that's done it.
You saw what he wrote on the wall.
It's not true, sir. l swear.
l never touched Mrs. Norris.
,
- Rubbish.
- lf l might, headmaster?
Perhaps Potter and his friends were simply
in the wrong place at the wrong time.
However...
...the circumstances are suspicious.
l, for one, don't recall
seeing Potter at dinner.
?
I'm afraid that's my doing, Severus.
You see, Harry was helping me
answer my fan mail.
That's why Ron and l
went looking for him, professor.
We'd just found him when he said...
..
- Yes, Miss Granger?
- When l said l wasn't hungry.
, ?
We were heading back to the common
room when we found Mrs. Norris.
- Innocent until proven guilty, Severus.
- My cat has been Petrified.
- l want to see some punishment!
- We will be able to cure her, Argus.
!
,
As l understand it, Madam Sprout
has a very healthy growth of Mandrake.
When matured, a potion will be made
which will revive Mrs. Norris.
And in the meantime...
...l strongly recommend caution...
...to all.
- It's a bit strange, isn't it?
- Strange?
, ?
?
You hear this voice,
a voice only you can hear...
...and then Mrs. Norris turns up
Petrified. It's just strange.
Do you think l should have told them?
Dumbledore and the others, l mean?
?
Are you mad?
No, Harry. Even in the wizarding world,
hearing voices isn't a good sign.
,
She's right, you know.
Could l have your attention,
please?
Right. Now, today,
we will be transforming animals...
...into water goblets.
Like so.
One, two, three.
vera verto.
", , "
" "
Now it's your turn.
Who would like to go first?
?
,
", , , "
Mr. Weasley.
"One, two, three. vera verto."
" "
vera verto!
That wand needs replacing,
Mr. Weasley.
?
- Yes, Miss Granger?
- Professor...
,
?
...l was wondering if you could tell us
about the Chamber of Secrets.
Very well.
You all know, of course...
1,000
...that Hogwarts was founded
over a thousand years ago...
...by the four greatest witches
and wizards of the age:
,
Godric Gryffindor,
Helga Hufflepuff...
...Rowena Ravenclaw
and Salazar Slytherin.
Now, three of the founders
coexisted quite harmoniously.
/
- One did not.
- Three guesses who.
Salazar Slytherin wished to be
more selective...
...about the students admitted
to Hogwarts.
He believed magical learning should
be kept within all-magic families.
In other words, pure-bloods.
Unable to sway the others,
he decided to leave the school.
Now, according to legend...
...Slytherin had built
a hidden chamber in this castle...
...known as the Chamber of Secrets.
Though, shortly before departing,
he sealed it...
...until that time when his own
true Heir returned to the school.
The Heir alone...
...would be able to open the Chamber...
...and unleash the horror within,
and by so doing...
...purge the school
of all those who...
...in Slytherin's view,
were unworthy to study magic.
Muggle-borns.
Naturally, the school
has been searched many times.
No such chamber has been found.
Professor? What exactly does legend
tell us lies within the Chamber?
?
The Chamber is said to be home
to something...
...that only the Heir of Slytherin
can control.
It is said to be the home...
...of a monster.
?
Do you think it's true? Do you think
there really is a Chamber of Secrets?
?
,
Yes. Couldn't you tell? McGonagall's
worried. All the teachers are.
lf there really is a Chamber of Secrets,
and it really has been opened, that means--
..
The Heir of Slytherin has returned
to Hogwarts. The question is, who is it?
Let's think. Who do we know who
thinks all Muggle-borns are scum?
?
- lf you're talking about Malfoy--
- Of course. You heard him.
,
"You'll be next, Mudbloods."
l heard him.
But Malfoy, the Heir of Slytherin?
,
Maybe Ron's right, Hermione.
l mean, look at his family.
The whole lot of them have been
in Slytherin for centuries.
?
Crabbe and Goyle must know.
Maybe we could trick them into telling.
?
Even they aren't that thick.
But there might be another way.
Mind you, it would be difficult.
Not to mention we'd be breaking
about 50 school rules...
...and it'll be dangerous.
Very dangerous.
,
Here it is.
The Polyjuice Potion.
'
"Properly brewed, the Polyjuice Potion
allows the drinker...
...to transform himself temporarily
into the physical form of another."
You mean if Harry and l drink that stuff,
we'll turn into Crabbe and Goyle?
?
- Wicked! Malfoy will tell us anything.
- Exactly.
But it's tricky. I've never seen
a more complicated potion.
?
- How long will it take to make?
- A month.
?
A month?
But, Hermione,
if Malfoy is the Heir of Slytherin...
...he could attack half
the Muggle-borns in the school by then.
l know.
But it's the only plan we've got.
Another goal for Slytherin!
90 30
They lead Gryffindor 90 to 30.
Yeah!
,
All right there, Scarhead?
, !
Watch yourself, Harry!
Wood, look out!
i
Blimey! Harry's got himself
a rogue Bludger.
That's been tampered with, that has.
I'll stop it.
No! Even with a proper wand,
it's too risky. You could hit Harry.
,
?
Training for the ballet, Potter?
You'll never catch me, Potter.
,
Let's go.
Harry Potter has caught the Snitch,
Gryffindor wins!
!
Finite Incantatem!
- Thank you.
- Are you okay?
?
,
No. l think my arm is broken.
Not to worry, Harry. l will fix
that arm of yours straightaway.
,
- Not you.
- Boy doesn't know what he's saying.
This won't hurt a bit.
", "
Brackium Emendo!
Yes, well,
that can sometimes happen...
..
...but the point is...
...you can no longer feel any pain, and,
very clearly, the bones are not broken.
?
Broken? There's no bones left.
Much more flexible, though.
,
Mr. Malfoy, stop making such a fuss.
You can go. Out of my way.
,
Should have been brought
straight to me.
..
l can mend bones in a heartbeat,
but growing them back...
?
You will be able to, won't you?
,
I'll be able to, certainly.
But it'll be painful.
You're in for a rough night, Potter.
Regrowing bones is a nasty business.
?
What do you expect?
Pumpkin juice?
Kill.
Time to kill.
Hello.
?
Dobby?
Harry Potter should have listened
to Dobby.
Harry Potter should have gone back home
when he missed the train.
It was you. You stopped the barrier
from letting Ron and me through.
Indeed. Yes, sir.
,
- You nearly got Ron and me expelled.
- At least you would be away from here.
Harry Potter must go home.
Dobby thought his Bludger would be
enough to make Harry Potter see--
?
Your Bludger? You made
that Bludger chase after me?
?
Dobby feels most aggrieved, sir.
Dobby had to iron his hands.
You better clear off before my bones
come back, Dobby, or l might strangle you.
Dobby is used to death threats, sir.
Dobby gets them five times a day at home.
l don't suppose you could tell me
why you're trying to kill me?
Not kill you, sir.
Never kill you.
,
Dobby remembers how it was
before Harry Potter triumphed...
...over He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named.
We house-elves were
treated like vermin, sir.
Of course, Dobby is still
treated like vermin.
, ?
Why do you wear that thing, Dobby?
?
This, sir? It is a mark
of the house-elf's enslavement.
Dobby can only be freed if his master
presents him with clothes.
,
Listen.
Listen!
Terrible things are
about to happen at Hogwarts.
Harry Potter must not stay here...
...now that history
is to repeat itself.
?
Repeat itself? You mean
this has happened before?
?
..
l shouldn't have said that.
,
- Bad Dobby! Bad!
- Stop it!
,
Stop it, Dobby!
Tell me. When did this happen before?
Who's doing it now?
?
Dobby cannot say, sir. Dobby
only wants Harry Potter to be safe.
,
?
No, Dobby. Tell me.
Who is it?
Put him here.
?
- What happened?
- There's been another attack.
l think he's been Petrified,
Madam Pomfrey.
Look. Perhaps he managed
to take a picture of his attacker.
?
, ?
What can this mean, Albus?
It means...
...that our students
are in great danger.
?
- What should l tell the staff?
- The truth.
Tell them Hogwarts
is no longer safe.
,
It is as we feared, Minerva.
The Chamber of Secrets
has indeed been opened again.
?
Again? You mean the Chamber
of Secrets has been opened before?
, ?
Of course.
Don't you see?
Lucius Malfoy must have opened it
when he was at school here.
- Now he's taught Draco how to do it.
- Maybe.
We'll have to wait for
the Polyjuice Potion to know for sure.
Enlighten me. Why are we brewing
this potion in broad daylight...
?
...in the middle of the girls' lavatory?
Don't you think we'll get caught?
?
No. No one ever comes in here.
,
?
- Why?
- Moaning Myrtle.
?
Who?
Moaning Myrtle.
?
- Who's Moaning Myrtle?
- I'm Moaning Myrtle.
!
l wouldn't expect you to know me.
Who would ever talk
about ugly, miserable...
...moping Moaning Myrtle?
She's a little sensitive.
Gather round!
!
Gather round.
Can everybody see me?
,
Can you all hear me?
Excellent.
In light of the dark events
of recent weeks...
...Professor Dumbledore has granted me
permission to start this Dueling Club...
...to train you all up in case
you ever need to defend yourselves...
...as l myself have done
on countless occasions.
For full details,
see my published works.
Let me introduce my assistant...
...Professor Snape.
He has sportingly agreed to help
with a short demonstration.
l don't want any of you
youngsters to worry.
You'll still have your Potions master
when I'm through with him. Never fear.
One.
Two.
- Three!
- Expelliarmus!
" "
?
- Do you think he's all right?
- Who cares?
An excellent idea to show them that,
Professor Snape...
...but if you don't mind me saying, it was
pretty obvious what you were about to do.
lf l had wanted to stop you,
it would have been only too easy.
Perhaps it would be prudent
to first teach the students...
...to block unfriendly spells,
professor.
,
An excellent suggestion,
Professor Snape.
Let's have a volunteer pair.
Potter, Weasley, how about you?
?
,
Weasley's wand causes devastation
with the simplest spells.
We'll be sending Potter
to the hospital wing in a matchbox.
?
Might l suggest someone
from my own house?
?
Malfoy, perhaps?
,
- Good luck, Potter.
- Thank you, sir.
!
Wands at the ready.
, ?
- Scared, Potter?
- You wish.
On the count of three...
...cast your charms to disarm
your opponent. Only to disarm.
,
We don't want any accidents here.
One.
- Two.
- Everte Statum!
Rictusempra!
l said disarm only.
Serpensortia!
,
Don't move, Potter.
I'll get rid of it for you.
,
Allow me, Professor Snape.
Alarte Ascendare!
Vipera Evanesca.
?
What are you playing at?
You're a Parselmouth?
Why didn't you tell us?
?
- I'm a what?
- You can talk to snakes.
?
l know. l accidentally set a python
on my cousin Dudley at the zoo once.
?
Once. But so what?
l bet loads of people here can do it.
?
,
No, they can't.
It's not a very common gift, Harry.
This is bad.
?
What's bad? lf l hadn't told
that snake not to attack Justin--
..
?
- That's what you said to it.
- You were there. You heard me.
,
l heard you speaking Parseltongue.
Snake language.
?
l spoke a different language?
But l didn't realize--
?
How can l speak a language
without knowing l can?
,
l don't know, but it sounded like you
were egging the snake on or something.
,
Harry, listen to me.
There's a reason the symbol
of Slytherin house is a serpent.
Salazar Slytherin was a Parselmouth.
He could talk to snakes too.
Exactly.
Now the whole school's gonna think
you're his great-great-great grandson.
But I'm not.
l can't be.
1,000
He lived a thousand years ago.
For all we know, you could be.
I'll see you back in the common room.
l want blood.
', '
They all must die.
Kill.
Time to kill.
,
?
Caught in the act.
I'll have you out this time, Potter.
Mark my words.
,
No. Mr. Filch! You don't understand--
Professor...
...l swear l didn't.
This is out of my hands, Potter.
Professor Dumbledore
will be waiting for you.
Sherbet Lemon.
?
Professor Dumbledore?
,
Bee in your bonnet, Potter?
..
l was just wondering
if you put me in the right house.
,
Yes. You were particularly
difficult to place.
But l stand by what l said last year.
You would have done well in Slytherin.
You're wrong.
Harry?
..
Professor.
, ..
Your bird...
There was nothing l could do.
..
- He just caught fire.
- And about time too.
He's been looking dreadful for days.
Pity you had to see him
on a burning day.
,
Fawkes is a phoenix, Harry.
They burst into flame
when it is time for them to die...
...and then they are...
...reborn from the ashes.
?
Fascinating creatures, phoenixes.
They can carry immensely heavy loads.
Their tears have healing powers.
Professor Dumbledore, sir!
Wait! Listen!
,
Professor Dumbledore, sir,
it wasn't Harry.
l'd be prepared to swear it
in front of the Ministry of Magic.
!
Relax.
l do not believe...
- ...that Harry attacked anyone.
- Of course you don't.
,
Right. Well, I'll...
- I'll just wait outside, then.
- Yes.
, ?
- You don't think it was me, professor?
- No, Harry.
,
l do not think it was you.
But l must ask you...
?
...is there something
you wish to tell me?
,
No, sir.
Nothing.
Very well, then.
Off you go.
Everything's set. We just need a bit
of who you're changing into.
/ ?
Crabbe and Goyle.
We also need to make sure
that the real Crabbe and Goyle...
...can't burst in on us
while we're interrogating Malfoy.
?
- How?
- I've got it all worked out.
l filled these
with a simple Sleeping Draught.
Simple, but powerful.
,
Now, once they're asleep...
...hide them in the broomstick cupboard
and pull out a few of their hairs...
...and put on their uniforms.
?
- Whose hair are you ripping out, then?
- I've already got mine.
Millicent Bulstrode. Slytherin.
l got this off her robes.
I'm going to go check
on the Polyjuice Potion.
Make sure that Crabbe and Goyle
find these.
,
Ron, maybe l should do it.
Yeah. Right.
" "
Wingardium Leviosa.
Cool.
?
How thick could you get?
Come on, let's get them.
We'll have exactly one hour
before we change back into ourselves.
Add the hairs.
Essence of Crabbe.
Cheers.
l think I'm gonna be sick.
Me too.
?
Harry?
Ron.
Bloody hell!
We still sound like ourselves.
You need to sound more like Crabbe.
- Bloody hell.
- Excellent.
?
- But where's Hermione?
- l...
,
l don't think I'm going.
You go on without me.
, ?
Hermione, are you okay?
Just go. You're wasting time.
Come on.
l think the Slytherin common room's
this way.
, !
Excuse me.
..
What are you doing d--?
?
l mean, what are you doing down here?
l happen to be a school prefect.
?
You, on the other hand, have no business
wandering the corridors at night.
?
What are your names again?
..
- I'm...
- Crabbe, Goyle, where have you two been?
, ,
?
Pigging out in the Great Hall
all this time?
?
Why are you wearing glasses?
..
- Reading.
- Reading?
?
l didn't know you could read.
, ?
And what are you doing down here,
Weasley?
,
Mind your attitude, Malfoy.
Well, sit down.
,
You'd never know the Weasleys
were pure-bloods, the way they behave.
They're an embarrassment
to the wizarding world. All of them.
, ?
What's wrong with you, Crabbe?
..
Stomachache.
You know, I'm surprised the Daily Prophet
hasn't done a report on all these attacks.
l suppose Dumbledore
is trying to hush it all up.
Father always said Dumbledore
was the worst thing...
- ...that ever happened to this place.
- You're wrong!
!
?
What?
You think there's someone here
who's worse than Dumbledore?
?
Well? Do you?
Harry Potter?
,
Good one, Goyle.
You're absolutely right.
Saint Potter.
And people actually think
that he's the Heir of Slytherin?
?
But then you must have some idea
who's behind it all.
,
You know l don't, Goyle.
l told you yesterday.
How many times do l have to tell you?
?
ls this yours?
But my father did say this:
It's been 50 years
since the Chamber was opened.
He wouldn't tell me who opened it.
Only that they were expelled.
The last time the Chamber of Secrets
was opened, a Mudblood died.
So it's only a matter of time
before one of them is killed this time.
As for me...
...l hope it's Granger.
, ?
What's the matter with you two?
You're acting very odd.
It's his stomachache.
Calm down.
..
Scar.
Hair.
, ?
Hey! Where are you going?
That was close.
,
Hermione, come out.
We've got loads to tell you.
!
Go away.
Wait till you see. It's awful.
, ?
Hermione?
Are you okay?
Do you remember me telling you...
?
...that the Polyjuice Potion
was only for human transformations?
It was cat hair l plucked off
Millicent Bulstrode's robes.
Look at my face.
Look at your tail.
?
Have you spoken to Hermione?
She should be out of hospital
in a few days...
...when she stops coughing up fur balls.
?
What's this?
Yuck!
Looks like Moaning Myrtle's
flooded the bathroom.
?
- Come to throw something else at me?
- Why would l throw something at you?
?
Don't ask me. Here l am,
minding my own business...
...and someone thinks it's funny
to throw a book at me.
But it can't hurt if someone
throws something at you.
l mean, it'll just go
right through you.
Sure! Let's all throw books at Myrtle
because she can't feel it.
10!
Ten points
if you get it through her stomach!
50!
Fifty points if it goes through her head!
?
- But who threw it at you, anyway?
- l don't know. l didn't see them.
l was just sitting in the U-bend,
thinking about death...
...and it fell through the top
of my head.
"Tom Marvolo Riddle."
My name...
...is Harry...
...Potter.
",
"
?
Do you know anything...
...about the Chamber of Secrets?
""
?
Can you...
...tell me?
""
"
" 50
"6 13"
Excuse me. Could you tell me
what's going on here?
?
Are you Tom Riddle?
, ?
Hello, can you hear me?
!
Riddle!
Come.
,
Professor Dumbledore.
?
Dumbledore?
, ?
It is not wise to be wandering around
this late hour, Tom.
,
Yes, professor. l suppose l...
l had to see for myself
if the rumors were true.
,
I'm afraid they are, Tom.
They are true.
?
About the school as well?
l don't have a home to go to.
,
They wouldn't really close Hogwarts,
would they, professor?
,
l understand, Tom, but I'm afraid...
...Headmaster Dippet
may have no choice.
?
Sir, if it all stopped,
if the person responsible was caught...
..
ls there something...
?
...you wish to tell me?
,
No, sir. Nothing.
Very well, then. Off you go.
,
Good night, sir.
- Let's get you out of there.
- Evening, Hagrid.
, ?
,
I'm going to have to turn you in, Hagrid.
l don't think you meant it to kill anyone...
,
You can't. You don't understand.
The dead girl's parents will be here
tomorrow. The least Hogwarts can do...
...is make sure the thing that killed
their daughter is slaughtered.
It wasn't him.
Aragog never killed no one. Never.
Monsters don't make good pets, Hagrid.
- Now, stand aside.
- No!
- Stand aside, Hagrid.
Cistem Aperio!
Arania Exumai!
, !
Aragog!
?
l can't let you go.
,
They'll have your wand for this, Hagrid.
You'll be expelled.
!
Hagrid!
It was Hagrid. Hagrid opened
the Chamber of Secrets 50 years ago.
It can't be Hagrid.
It just can't be.
We don't even know this Tom Riddle.
He sounds like a dirty, rotten snitch to me.
,
The monster had killed somebody, Ron.
What would any of us have done?
?
Look, Hagrid's our friend. Why don't
we just go and ask him about it?
That would be a cheerful visit.
"Hello, Hagrid.
, ?
Tell us, have you been setting anything
mad and hairy loose in the castle lately?"
?
, ?
Mad and hairy? You wouldn't be talking
about me, now, would you?
?
No.
. ?
What's that you've got, Hagrid?
,
It's Flesh-Eating Slug Repellent.
For the Mandrakes, you know.
Now, according to Professor Sprout,
they've still got a bit of growing up to do.
But once their acne's cleared up, we'll
be able to chop them up and stew them...
...and then we'll get those people
down at the hospital un-Petrified.
In the meantime, though, you three...
...had best be looking after yourselves.
All right?
?
, ?
Hello, Neville.
,
Harry, l don't know who did it,
but you'd better come.
Come on!
It had to be a Gryffindor.
Nobody else knows our password.
Unless it wasn't a student.
Whoever it was, they must have
been looking for something.
And they found it.
Tom Riddle's diary is gone.
,
All right, listen up.
We play our game,
Hufflepuff doesn't stand a chance.
,
?
We're stronger, quicker and smarter.
Not to mention they're dead scared
that Harry will Petrify them...
- ...if they fly anywhere near him.
- Well, that too.
Professor McGonagall.
- This match has been canceled.
- We can't cancel Quidditch.
?
,
Silence, Wood. You and your teammates
will go to Gryffindor Tower. Now.
,
Potter, you and l will find Mr. Weasley.
There's something
the both of you have to see.
l warn you.
This could be a wee bit of a shock.
Hermione!
She was found near the library...
...along with this.
,
?
Does it mean anything to either of you?
No.
Could l have your attention, please?
Because of recent events, these new rules
will be put into effect immediately:
"All students will return to their house
common rooms by 6:00 every evening.
All students will be escorted
to each lesson by a teacher.
No exceptions."
l should tell you this:
Unless the culprit
behind these attacks is caught...
...it is likely the school will be closed.
We've got to talk to Hagrid, Ron.
l can't believe it's him...
,
...but if he did set the monster loose
last time...
...he'll know how to get inside
the Chamber of Secrets. That's a start.
?
But you heard McGonagall.
We're not allowed to leave
the tower except for class.
l think it's time to get
my dad's old cloak out again.
?
Who's there?
Hello?
?
- What's that for?
- Nothing. l was expecting...
..
It doesn't matter. Come on in.
l just made a pot of tea.
Hagrid, are you okay?
, ?
I'm fine. I'm all right.
,
Did you hear about Hermione?
?
Yeah. l heard about that, all right.
,
Look, we have to ask you something.
?
Do you know who's opened
the Chamber of Secrets?
What you had to understand
about that is--
Quick, under the cloak.
Don't say a word.
Be quiet, both of you.
- Professor Dumbledore, sir.
- Good evening, Hagrid.
, ?
l wonder, could we...?
?
Of course. Come in. Come in.
,
That's Dad's boss.
Cornelius Fudge, Minister of Magic.
Bad business, Hagrid, very bad business.
Had to come.
,
Three attacks on Muggle-borns.
Things have gone far enough.
- The Ministry's got to act.
- But l never--
You know l never, professor.
,
l want it understood, Cornelius...
...that Hagrid...
...has my full confidence.
Albus, look,
Hagrid's record is against him.
,
- I've got to take him.
- Take me?
?
Take me where?
Not Azkaban prison.
?
I'm afraid we have no choice, Hagrid.
,
Already here, Fudge?
Good.
What are you doing here?
Get out of my house!
?
Believe me...
...l take absolutely no pleasure
being inside your...
You call this a house?
?
No.
l simply called up the school
and was told the headmaster was here.
Well, what exactly is it
that you want with me?
?
The other governors and l have decided
it's time for you to step aside.
This is an order of suspension.
You'll find all 12 signatures on it.
I'm afraid we feel
you've rather lost your touch.
..
Well, what, with all these attacks...
...there'll be no
Muggle-borns left at Hogwarts.
l can only imagine what an awful loss
that would be to the school.
You can't take
Professor Dumbledore away.
Take him away and the Muggle-borns
won't stand a chance.
You mark my words,
there'll be killings next!
You think so?
,
Calm yourself, Hagrid.
lf the governors desire my removal...
...l will, of course, step aside.
However...
...you will find that help
will always be given at Hogwarts...
...to those who...
...ask for it.
Admirable sentiments.
Shall we?
?
Fudge.
Come, Hagrid.
,
Well?
lf...
lf anybody was looking for some stuff...
...then all they'd have to do
would be to follow the spiders.
Yep. That would lead them right.
,
That's all l have to say.
And someone will need
to feed Fang while I'm away.
Good boy.
Hagrid's right.
With Dumbledore gone,
there'll be an attack a day.
Look.
Come on.
,
Come on, Fang.
Come on.
?
What?
You heard what Hagrid said.
"Follow the spiders."
?
They're heading to the Dark Forest.
Why spiders? Why couldn't it be
"follow the butterflies"?
,
Harry, l don't like this.
/
- Harry, l don't like this at all.
- Shush!
Can we go back now?
?
Come on.
Who is it?
?
Don't panic.
Hagrid?
?
ls that you?
We're friends of Hagrid's.
,
?
And you?
You're Aragog, aren't you?
Yes.
,
Hagrid has never sent
men into our hollow before.
He's in trouble. Up at the school,
there have been attacks.
They think it's Hagrid.
They think he opened
the Chamber of Secrets. Like before.
That's a lie.
Hagrid never opened
the Chamber of Secrets.
- Then you're not the monster?
- No.
The monster was born in the castle.
l came to Hagrid from a distant land
in the pocket of a traveler.
Harry.
But if you're not the monster, then
what did kill that girl 50 years ago?
?
We do not speak of it.
It is an ancient creature we
spiders fear above all others.
But have you seen it?
?
l never saw any part of the castle
but the box in which Hagrid kept me.
The girl was discovered
in a bathroom.
When l was accused,
Hagrid brought me here.
- Harry!
- What?
?
Well, thank you.
We'll just go.
Go?
?
l think not.
My sons and daughters
do not harm Hagrid on my command.
But l cannot deny them
fresh meat...
...when it wanders
so willingly into our midst.
Goodbye, friend of Hagrid.
,
Can we panic now?
?
Know any spells?
One, but it's not powerful
enough for all of them.
?
Where's Hermione when you need her?
Let's go!
Arania Exumai!
Go!
Glad we're out of there.
Arania Exumai!
- Thanks for that.
- Don't mention it.
Get us out of here.
!
Now!
, !
!
Come on!
Come on, move faster!
Come on! Go!
!
Get us in the air.
The flying gear's jammed!
!
, !
- Come on! Pull!
- I'm trying!
!
?
Follow the spiders.
lf Hagrid ever gets out of Azkaban,
I'll kill him.
l mean, what was the point
of sending us in there?
?
- What have we found out?
- We know one thing.
Hagrid never opened
the Chamber of Secrets.
He was innocent.
Wish you were here, Hermione.
We need you.
Now more than ever.
- What's that?
- Ron...
?
This is why Hermione was in
the library the day she was attacked.
Come on.
"Of the many fearsome beasts
that roam our land...
'
...none is more deadly than the basilisk.
Capable of living for hundreds of years...
'
...instant death awaits any who meet
this giant serpent's eye.
'
Spiders flee before it."
Ron, this is it.
,
The monster in the Chamber
of Secrets is a basilisk.
That's why l can hear it speak.
It's a snake.
But if it kills by looking people
in the eye, why is it no one's dead?
?
Because no one did look it
in the eye.
Not directly, at least.
Colin saw it through his camera.
Justin-- Justin must have seen
the basilisk through Nearly Headless Nick.
Nick got the full blast of it.
But he's a ghost, he couldn't die again.
..
And Hermione had the mirror.
l bet you she was using it to look
around corners in case it came along.
?
And Mrs. Norris?
I'm pretty sure she didn't have
a camera or a mirror, Harry.
The water.
,
There was water on the floor that night.
She only saw the basilisk's reflection.
' '
"Spiders flee before it."
- It all fits.
- But how's a basilisk been getting around?
?
A dirty, great snake.
Someone would have seen it.
- Hermione's answered that too.
- Pipes? It's using the plumbing.
,
Remember what Aragog said
about that girl 50 years ago?
?
She died in a bathroom?
What if she never left?
?
Moaning Myrtle.
"
All students are to return
to their house dormitories at once,
"
All teachers to the second-floor
corridor immediately,
As you can see, the Heir of Slytherin
has left another message.
Our worst fear has been realized.
A student has been taken by the monster
into the Chamber itself.
The students must be sent home.
I'm afraid this is the end of Hogwarts.
,
?
So sorry. Dozed off.
What have l missed?
A girl has been snatched by the monster,
Lockhart. Your moment has come at last.
,
?
- My moment?
- Weren't you saying just last night...
?
...that you've known all along where
the entrance to the Chamber of Secrets is?
That's settled. We'll leave you
to deal with the monster, Gilderoy.
,
- Your skills, after all, are legend.
- Very well.
I'll just be in my office getting...
..
Getting ready.
?
Who is it that the monster's taken,
Minerva?
Ginny Weasley.
'
"Her skeleton will lie
in the Chamber forever."
Ginny.
Lockhart may be useless, but he's
going to try and get into the Chamber.
At least we can tell him
what we know.
Professor, we have some information
for you.
,
?
Are you going somewhere?
Well, yes. Urgent call. Unavoidable.
Got to go.
, , ..
?
- What about my sister?
- Well...
As to that, most unfortunate.
No one regrets more than l.
, ..
..
?
You're the Defense Against the Dark
Arts teacher. You can't go now.
l must say, when l took the job,
there was nothing in the description--
?
You're running away?
- After all you did in your books?
- Books can be misleading.
?
- You wrote them.
- My dear boy, do use your common sense.
,
My books wouldn't have sold half as well
if people didn't think l'd done those things.
You're a fraud.
You've been taking credit
for what other wizards have done.
ls there anything you can do?
?
Yes, now you mention it.
I'm rather gifted with Memory Charms.
Otherwise, all those wizards
would have gone blabbing.
l'd never have sold another book.
In fact, I'm going to have to do
the same to you.
Don't even think about it.
?
Who's there?
,
Hello, Harry.
?
- What do you want?
- To ask you how you died.
?
It was dreadful.
It happened right here
in this very cubicle.
l'd hidden because Olive Hornby
was teasing me about my glasses.
l was crying, and then
l heard somebody come in.
, ?
- Who was it, Myrtle?
- l don't know. l was distraught!
,
But they said something funny,
a kind of made-up language.
And l realized it was a boy, so l unlocked
the door to tell him to go away and...
" "
- ...l died.
- Just like that? How?
?
l just remember seeing a pair
of great, big, yellow eyes...
...over there by that sink.
This is it.
,
This is it, Ron. l think this is
the entrance to the Chamber of Secrets.
Say something. Harry,
say something in Parseltongue.
,
..
Excellent, Harry. Good work.
Well, then, I'll just be...
There's no need for me to stay.
Yes, there is.
- You first.
- Now, boys, what good will it do?
,
Better you than us.
But-- Obviously, yes.
..
Sure you don't want to test it first?
It's really quite filthy down here.
,
- All right. Let's go.
- Oh, Harry?
lf you die down there,
you're welcome to share my toilet.
,
Thanks, Myrtle.
Now, remember: Any sign of movement,
close your eyes straightaway.
Go on.
This way.
?
- What's this?
- It looks like a snake.
- It's a snakeskin.
- Bloody hell.
Whatever shed this must be
60 feet long. Or more.
,
Heart of a lion, this one.
The adventure ends here, boys.
But don't fret.
The world will know our story.
How l was too late to save the girl.
How you two
tragically lost your minds...
...at the sight of her mangled body.
So...
,
You first, Mr. Potter.
Say goodbye to your memories.
Obliviate!
!
! ?
- Ron! Ron, are you okay?
- I'm fine.
?
Hello.
Who are you?
- Ron Weasley.
- Really?
?
..
And who am l?
Lockhart's Memory Charm backfired.
He hasn't got a clue who he is.
,
It's an odd sort of place, isn't it?
?
Do you live here?
- No.
- Really?
?
- What do l do now?
- You wait here...
?
...and try and shift some of this rock
so we can get back through.
- I'll go on and find Ginny.
- Okay.
Ginny! Ginny, please don't be dead.
Wake up, wake up.
,
!
Please wake up.
She won't wake.
, ..
Tom. Tom Riddle.
What do you mean, she won't wake?
?
, ..
- She's not...?
- She's still alive, but only just.
?
- Are you a ghost?
- A memory...
...preserved in a diary for 50 years.
,
She's cold as ice.
Ginny, please don't be dead. Wake up.
You've got to help me, Tom.
There's a basilisk.
,
It won't come until it's called.
- Give me my wand, Tom.
- You won't be needing it.
- We've got to go. We've got to save her.
- I'm afraid l can't do that.
,
You see, as poor Ginny grows weaker,
l grow stronger.
?
Yes, Harry, it was Ginny Weasley
who opened the Chamber of Secrets.
,
No. She couldn't. She wouldn't.
It was Ginny who set the basilisk
on the Mudbloods and Filch's cat...
...Ginny who wrote the threatening
messages on the walls.
?
- But why?
- Because l told her to.
You'll find l can be very persuasive.
Not that she knew what she was doing.
She was, shall we say,
in a kind of trance.
Still, the power of the diary
began to scare her.
She tried to dispose of it
in the girls' bathroom.
And then who should find it but you?
,
The very person
l was most anxious to meet.
?
And why did you want to meet me?
l knew l had to talk to you,
meet you if l could.
So l decided to show you my capture
of that brainless oaf Hagrid...
- ...to gain your trust.
- Hagrid's my friend.
!
- And you framed him, didn't you?
- It was my word against Hagrid's.
Only Dumbledore seemed to think
he was innocent.
I'll bet Dumbledore saw
right through you.
He certainly kept an annoyingly close
watch on me after that.
l knew it wouldn't be safe to open the
Chamber again while l was still at school...
...so l decided to leave behind
a diary...
...preserving my 16-year-old self
in its pages...
...so that one day
l would be able to lead another...
...to finish Salazar Slytherin's
noble work.
Well, you haven't finished it
this time.
In a few hours, the Mandrake Draught
will be ready.
And everyone who was Petrified
will be all right again.
?
Haven't l told you? Killing Mudbloods
doesn't matter to me anymore.
For many months now,
my new target has been you.
How is it that a baby
with no extraordinary magical talent...
?
...was able to defeat the greatest wizard
of all time?
How did you escape with nothing
but a scar...
?
...while Lord Voldemort's powers
were destroyed?
?
Why do you care how l escaped?
Voldemort was after your time.
Voldemort is my past,
present and future.
,
" "
You. You're the Heir of Slytherin.
- You're Voldemort.
- Surely you didn't think...
?
...l was going to keep
my filthy Muggle father's name?
No. l fashioned myself a new name,
a name l knew wizards everywhere...
,
...would one day fear to speak when l
became the greatest sorcerer in the world.
Albus Dumbledore
is the greatest sorcerer in the world.
Dumbledore's been driven out of
this castle by the mere memory of me.
He'll never be gone. Not as long as
those who remain are loyal to him.
Fawkes?
So this is what Dumbledore
sends his great defender.
A songbird and an old hat.
Let's match the power of Lord Voldemort,
Heir of Salazar Slytherin...
...against the famous Harry Potter.
,
Parseltongue won't save you now,
Potter. It only obeys me.
No!
!
Your bird may have blinded the basilisk,
but it can still hear you.
Yes, Potter.
The process is nearly complete.
,
In a few minutes, Ginny Weasley will be
dead, and l will cease to be a memory.
Lord Voldemort will return...
...very much alive.
Ginny?
Remarkable, isn't it...
...how quickly the venom
of the basilisk penetrates the body?
l'd guess you have little more
than a minute to live.
You'll be with your dear
Mudblood mother soon, Harry.
Funny, the damage a silly
little book can do...
...especially in the hands
of a silly little girl.
?
What are you doing?
!
Stop. No!
It was me.
But l swear, l didn't mean to.
,
..
Riddle made me, and...
Harry, you're hurt.
,
Don't worry.
Ginny, you need
to get yourself out.
Follow the Chamber
and you'll find Ron.
,
You were brilliant, Fawkes.
l just wasn't quick enough.
Of course.
Phoenix tears have healing powers.
,
Thanks.
It's all right, Ginny.
It's over.
It's just a memory.
!
Amazing!
This is just like magic!
!
You both realize, of course...
...that in the past few hours, you have
broken perhaps a dozen school rules.
Yes, sir.
,
?
There is sufficient evidence
to have you both expelled.
,
Yes, sir.
Therefore, it is only fitting...
...that you both receive...
...Special Awards for Services
to the School.
Thanks, sir.
Now, Mr. Weasley, if you would...
...have an owl deliver these
release papers to Azkaban.
l believe we want
our gamekeeper back.
First, l want to thank you, Harry.
You must have shown me
real loyalty down in the Chamber.
Nothing but that
could have called Fawkes to you.
And...
...second...
...l sense that something
is troubling you.
..?
Am l right, Harry?
..
It's just...
You see, sir, l couldn't help
but notice certain things, certain...
,
..
Certain similarities
between Tom Riddle and me.
l see.
Well, you can speak
Parseltongue, Harry. Why?
Because Lord Voldemort
can speak Parseltongue.
,
lf I'm not mistaken, Harry...
...he transferred
some of his powers to you...
...the night he gave you that scar.
?
Voldemort transferred
some of his powers to me?
Not intentionally...
...but yes.
So the Sorting Hat was right.
l should be in Slytherin.
?
,
It's true. You possess many of the
qualities that Voldemort himself prizes.
Determination, resourcefulness...
...and if l may say so,
a certain disregard for the rules.
Why, then, did the Sorting Hat
place you in Gryffindor?
- Because l asked it to.
- Exactly, Harry. Exactly.
,
Which makes you different
from Voldemort.
It is not our abilities
that show what we truly are.
It is our choices.
lf you want proof
why you belong in Gryffindor...
...then l suggest
you look more closely at this.
Be careful.
Godric Gryffindor.
It would take a true Gryffindor
to pull that out of the hat.
Dobby.
So this is your master.
The family you serve is the Malfoys.
I'll deal with you later.
,
Out of my way, Potter.
So it's true. You have returned.
When the governors learned that
Arthur Weasley's daughter...
...was taken into the Chamber,
they saw fit to summon me back.
- Ridiculous.
- Curiously, Lucius, several of them...
...were under the impression
that you would curse their family...
...if they did not agree
to suspend me in the first place.
- How dare you!
- Beg your pardon?
My sole concern has always been
and will always be...
...the welfare of this school...
...and, of course, its students.
The culprit has been identified,
l presume?
Yes.
?
And?
Who was it?
Voldemort.
Only this time he chose to act
through somebody else...
...by means of this.
l see.
Fortunately, our young Mr. Potter
discovered it.
One hopes that no more of Lord
Voldemort's old school-things...
...should find their way
into innocent hands.
The consequences for the one
responsible would be...
...severe.
Well, let us hope...
...that Mr. Potter will always
be around to save the day.
,
Don't worry. l will be.
Dumbledore.
,
Come, Dobby. We're leaving.
Sir?
l wonder if l could have that?
?
Mr. Malfoy.
,
Mr. Malfoy!
l have something of yours.
Mine? l don't know
what you're talking about.
?
l think you do, sir.
l think you slipped the diary
into Ginny Weasley's cauldron...
...that day at Diagon Alley.
, ?
You do, do you?
Why don't you prove it?
,
Come, Dobby.
Open it.
Dobby.
!
Master has given Dobby a sock.
?
..
What? l didn't give--
Master has presented Dobby
with clothes.
Dobby is free.
!
You lost me my servant!
You shall not harm Harry Potter.
Your parents were
meddlesome fools too.
,
Mark my words, Potter.
One day soon...
...you are going to meet
the same sticky end.
Harry Potter freed Dobby.
How can Dobby ever repay him?
?
- Just promise me something.
- Anything, sir.
Never try to save my life again.
,
- Welcome back, Sir Nicholas.
- Thank you.
,
- Good evening, Sir Nicholas.
- Good evening.
, ?
,
- Good to see you, Sir Nicholas.
- Thank you.
,
Hello.
- Hermione! Welcome back.
- Thanks, Sir Nicholas.
!
,
Harry. It's Hermione.
, ,
- Welcome back, Hermione.
- It's good to be back.
,
Congratulations.
l can't believe you solved it.
We had loads of help from you.
- We couldn't have done it without you.
- Thanks.
Could l have your attention, please?
Before we begin the feast...
...let us have a round of applause
for Professor Sprout, Madam Pomfrey...
...whose Mandrake juice has been
so successfully administered...
...to all who had been Petrified.
Also, in light of the recent events...
...as a school treat...
...all exams have been canceled.
Oh, no.
Sorry I'm late.
The owl that delivered my release papers
got all lost and confused.
Some ruddy bird called Errol.
And l'd just like to say that if it hadn't
been for you, Harry and Ron...
...and Hermione, of course...
..
...l would still be you-know-where...
...so l'd just like to say thanks.
,
There's no Hogwarts
without you, Hagrid.